[
  {
    "question":"Which of the following command is used to create react-js-app ?",
    "options":["npx create-react-app appname","npm install create-react-app","npx install create-react-app -g","install - l create-react-app"],
    "answer":"npx create-react-app appname"
  },
  {
    "question":"In React.js which one of the following is used to create a class for Inheritance ?",
    "options":["Create","Extends","Inherits","Delete"],
    "answer":"Extends"

  },
  {
    "question":"What is the default port number in which the application run ?",
    "options":["3000","8080","5000","3030"],
    "answer":"3000"

  },
  {
    "question":"Which of the following valid component return type of React ?",
    "options":["2","5","1","3"],
    "answer":"1"

  },
  {
    "question":"Which of the following is a way to handle data in React.js ?",
    "options":["State & Props","Services & Components","State & Services","State & Component"],
    "answer":"State & Props"

  },
  {
    "question":"Which of the following is must for the API in React.js ?",
    "options":["SetinitialComponent","renderComponent","render","All of the above"],
    "answer":"renderComponent"

  },
  {
    "question":"Which of the following is true regarding Babel ?",
    "options":["Compiler","Transpilar","Both of the above","None of the above"],
    "answer":"Both of the above"

  },
  {
    "question":"In React.js, how we can pass the data from one component to another in React.js ?",
    "options":["SetState","Render with arguments","Props","PropTypes"],
    "answer":"Props"

  },
  {
    "question":"Which of the following function is true about changing the state in React.js ?",
    "options":["this.State{}","this.setState","this.setChangeState","All of the above"],
    "answer":"this.setState"

  },
  {
    "question":"Which of the following method is true about referring parent class in React.js ?",
    "options":["self()","inherits()","this()","super()"],
    "answer":"super()"

  }
]

